Nilesh Ajit Manohar

23 Szechenyi Utca, Ukk, Hungary - 8347

Nationality : Indian

Visa Status: Valid Visa till August 2015. E Mail Address : <u>nilesh.manohar@gmail.com</u>

Profile Summary:

Software Developer with 12 years experience in Web Application Development and Maintenance. Experience in Java, Java Based Applications, PHP, Ajax, JavaScript, Web 2.0, CSS. Posses necessary skills for Web Application Development using the latest technologies available. Experience in Software Development Life Cycle, Managing and coaching team members.

Key Achievements:

- Designed and Developed the version2 application for webtext.com
- SMS Enabled Clinic Management
- Designed and developed a customised CMS system with SEO urls.
- Developed single page application using javascript, json and ajax for TMobile
- Developed UI for mobile phones to emulate popular social networking site.
- Involved in development of reporting system using ajax on jboss application server.
- Designed and Developed Content managed multilingual help system.
- Internationalized the software product written in PHP to cater for all major European languages.
- Developed a transparent NTLM authentication for a product in Java.
- Developed a user interface and printing solution while working in AIB.
- Developed and delivered an Installation Program for Installing Purchasing Expert on Client Machine and had given a demonstration to a team of 7 people in Bracknell, UK on the same so that the team could install the software on the client machine without any technical assistance.
- Developed a cross browser code in DHTML for the User Interface of the product.
- Release Manager for the Internationalization of the product where a new release process was implemented which reduced the building process of the final deliverable by 50% and the success rate at the first cycle of QA test was increased to 80%.
- Designed and developed programs such as search engine, chat program and other utilities in Perl for the portal site http://www.sholay.com.

Education and Certifications:

- **Masters in Opto-Electronics and Optical Information Processing** from The Queen's University of Belfast, UK 1996-97 (was placed second in a class of 30 students)
- Masters in Physics from Osmania University, India 1993-95 with First Class
- **B.Sc. in Math's, Physics & Electronics** from Osmania University, India 1990-93 with First Class.
- Object Oriented Analysis and Design using Rational Rose Certification, Dublin.
- Trained Green Belt in Six Sigma Methodologies.
- **Java 1** Certification from http://www.brainbench.com
- JavaScript Certification from http://www.brainbench.com

Awards:

- Scholarship under the Overseas Development Shared Scholarship Scheme awarded by the Association of Commonwealth Universities and The Queen's University of Belfast on behalf of British Government for the Masters course at The Queen's University of Belfast.
- Merit Hindi Scholarship awarded by Govt. of Andhra Pradesh for Meritorious Non-Hindi speaking students.
- Award of Excellence by General Electric Global eXchange Services for Outstanding Professional Initiative and Performance.

IT Skills:

Operating Systems:

Linux, Mac OS X, Windows VISTA. Windows XP

Technologies:

Java, PERL, JavaScript, XML, XSL, Ajax, JSON, CSS, Web 2.0, PHP, JSP, Tag Libraries, Servlets, RMI Knowledge of EJB's, J2EE, STRUTS, CakePHP, CodeIgniter, MooTools, Prototype, Scriptaculous, JQuery, BluePrintCss, Grid Framework, Grails, Twitter Bootstrap, Node.js, Angular.js

Databases:

SQL Server 7.0, Oracle 8.1.7, MySql, InterBase, PostgreSql

Tools & IDE:

IntelliJ, Oracle J Builder, eXcelon Stylus Studio 3.0, Visual J++ 6.0, Forte for Java, IBM Websphere Application Studio, Visual Café 3.0, MS FrontPage, Adobe Photo Shop 5.0, DreamWeaver MX, Flash MX, PVCS, Eclipse, Netbeans, Perforce

Servers:

Apache, Tomcat, IIS 5.0, Weblogic, Jetty, Geronimo, Websphere, Crystal Reports

Work Experience:

Director, NEAL Technologies Kft., Apr 2011-till date

Upgrade jQuery, jQuery UI and TinyMCE for TerminalFour's SiteManager product
Designed and Developed the version2 application for webtext.com
Designed and Developed http://www.find-me-a.biz
SMS Enabled Clinic Management - http://www.webtext.com/sms-enabled-clinic-management-software-from-webtext/

Web UI Developer, Terminal Four, May 2009 - Nov 2010

Involved in rebranding the admin interface on the CMS System. The process involved developing javascript solution taking to Web Services.

Web Developer, Critical Path, Dublin June 2008 - May 2009

Currently working as a Web Developer developing the corporate, intranet and support site using Cake PHP framework and Oracle.

Web UI Developer, Newbay, Dublin June 2007 – June 2008

As a Web UI Developer have developed UI for Mobile Phones to emulate a popular social networking site using JSP's and Wall Tag Library. Designed and Developed Report screens for Customer Care tool using Django framewrok. Developed a popular film based blog using JSP's. Developed a single page application using prototype, scriptaculous, ajax and JSON for TMobile.

Senior Web Developer, Denobi, Dublin November 2006 – June 2007(Fixed Term Contract)

As a Senior Web Developer involved in Designing and Co-ordinating with Team in India to execute the project. Developed CMS system based on MVC framework in PHP. Worked on various projects which involved using, customising open source e commerce project (osCommerce)

Web Developer, Paddy Power, Dublin November 2005 - November 2006

As a web developer involved in developing and maintaining web applications. Have designed and developed a content managed multilingual help system. Currently rewriting php code to cater to new database schema. I am responsible for maintenance of several microsites. I also have worked on Risk Project, wherein I had developed customer screens using JSP, AJAX, DHTML running on JBoss. I also have developed few prototype application using Yahoo Widget Engine.

Web Developer, Shopecentre, Dublin October 2004 - November 2005

As a web developer involved in developing and bug fixing company's solution which uses Oracle, Apache and PHP. Introduced CVS and Bug Tracking system Mantis. Developed a Internationalized version of the solution to cater for all major European locales. Currently developing a CMS solution.

Software Developer, Skillsoft, Dublin July 2004 – October 2004 (Fixed term contract)

As a software developer I was involved in bug fixing for the company's e-; earning offline solution. Over there I developed a transparent NTLM authentication solution for the product.

Software Developer, AIB, Dublin Nov 2003 – June 2004 (Fixed term contract)

As a software developer I was involved in developing backend and front-end services for Lending department using Java, XML, XSL, Websphere and Tomcat. Developed a solution for cross – browser grid (in JavaScript) to display tables and also developed a printing solution.

Software Developer Segala Solutions Limited, Dublin March 2003 - Nov 2003

As a Software Developer currently developing Time Sheet and Invoice Management Program using PHP on Apache for Internet and STRUTS and Tomcat for Intranet. Currently working as a Contractor for O2 developing Automated Test Scripts to query the LDAP and Mail Servers.

Software Engineer GE Global eXchange Services, Dublin Sep 1999 – April 2002

As a Software Engineer I was involved in developing and maintaining Purchasing Expert. Purchasing Expert is a web-based e – procurement application that helps to

streamline the internal purchasing process. Purchasing Expert is a 3-tier product being developed using Java, RMI and JDBC. Purchasing Expert runs on Weblogic BEA Server Ver 5.1 with MS SQL Server 7.0, MS SQL Server 2000, Oracle 7.1 and Oracle 8.x as backend databases. During this period I was involved in Code Bug Fixing and the following projects were successfully completed.

- OLAF (One Look And Feel) The existing User Interface was modified to be in sync with the GE standards.
- 2. **Internationalization** Release Manager for this project. Project involved Internationalizing the existing product so that then it could be localized into any language (provided they are supported by Java and the Database used) including Double Byte languages like Japanese. This project also involved upgrading from Weblogic 3.1.8 to 5.1.0
- 3. **TPNM** Involved connecting to an External Product Catalogue and enabling the users to buy products from an external supplier.

Programmer Netangle Com. Pvt. LTD, Hyderabad, India Aug 1998 – Aug 1999

As a Programmer main function was to develop utilities and programs for the portal site http://www.sholay.com. These programs were developed using Perl, JavaScript and HTML. The Programs developed were as follows

- 1. Search Engine Written in Perl the Search Engine has two options one the General Search and the second a specific search. The specific search gives the user options of Categories to carry out his search. The specific search is designed to display specific information as needed by the client rather than to displaying all the matches for the client query. The database used is a Flat File generated from MS-Access.
- 2. On-line search for Computer Professional Perl program in order to carry out the search using MS Access as back end Database.
- 3. Chat Program This program lets users to log on to the Chat channel after verifying the user name (for duplicates). The Chat Programs also has features like sending Pvt. Messages and changing to different rooms. The Chat Program also has an Administrator who can ban an IP address from logging onto the channel.

Being a member of a small team I was able to pick up working knowledge of many tools and application like DreamWeaver, Adobe PhotoShop, Flash and basic of Internet Information Server Management.

References: Provided on Request.